hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so today uh we are going to
discuss about a problem uh which is
quite common when you are working with
uh web applications you might come
across scenarios where you get these
popups which are mostly JavaScript
enabled right now these popups will not
be recognized by the tosa application
engine which can recognize most of the
applications but these windows will not
be recognized by this particular
technology so in these type of scenarios
you need to fall back upon different
engines and one of the engine which is
called the U IIA engine you can use this
UIA scan to scan these popup Windows
which are Java Script based and through
this you can solve this particular
problem where you're not able to
identify these particular popup Windows
okay so let's see uh with the help of an
example uh how we can go around this
particular problem and how we can solve
this easily with the different scanning
methods which are available in tosa so
for this um I have gone to this
particular website which has got some
JavaScript alerts okay and here uh I can
go ahead and click any of these
different alerts okay so I can click
this one and you here it will say um I
am a JS alert it is a popup window which
comes on top of this particular browser
right so let's see uh if we are able to
scan this with the normal application
uh option which we choose to scan any
particular
window so we'll go back to tosa and here
in the modules we'll go ahead and choose
scan application okay so let's go ahead
and scan this particular application
along with the popup so we'll try
this okay so now you can see that uh
tosa has scanned some elements uh it has
scanned all these buttons
and some links here but uh I still
cannot see the windows popup here right
so I'm going to increase the filtered
items and try to see if I can still see
this particular controls which are
present on this popup okay so if I go
through the whole tree I cannot see this
popup okay or or any controls which are
present in this
popup so mostly uh tosa will not be able
to scan this JavaScript alert popup okay
when you choose the application option
so we will see what is the work around
for this okay so we'll close this and we
will try to scan this
again so initially we have to select
application because there is no specific
method uh present there but once you
come to this xcan window here you can
choose different options okay so once
the window window is selected now what
you can do right click on that and by
default HTML is selected right but we
have got different options and we are
going to use the UIA option okay so it's
one of the scanning engines uh which can
scan some window based controls or even
JavaScript based controls okay so we are
going to use this particular scanning
technology and then we are going to
click on
scan
and now you will see that uh it has
scanned uh different controls right here
uh you can see many other controls but
the main control which we are looking
for is the popup or the alert right and
it is present right here you can see so
here uh we can just select the okay
button because we want to click on okay
to proceed with our um automation right
because this is completely blocking the
automation so we want to click on okay
and then we want to proceed with our
next steps so as you can see uh the okay
button is uh unique so we don't need to
do anything here okay uh I'm going to go
ahead and save this I will change the
name here I will say
JavaScript
popup okay and go ahead and save this
now and close
this
so now coming back here uh you can see
that this module has been created now if
you want to use this module as a generic
module right because most of the
JavaScript alerts will have this kind of
text so it will start with uh some um
application related name and then it
will say says okay this is mostly how
the JavaScript alerts or popups have the
same name so here what we can do is
instead of this uh we can put a regular
expression here okay so that uh it can
cover any particular page title um or
the title of that popup right so so
whatever uh it begins with that can be
covered with the regular expression
Aster and then you can uh put say here
okay now uh we will go ahead and we will
create a new test case let's create a
new test case under the the same folder
which is Win controls okay so here we
will say uh
click on
popup okay and then we will go ahead and
add the module
here and here what we need to do we just
need to click on it
right so that's all uh we have to do
here and then let's go ahead and uh run
this in
scratchbook okay so as you can see now
it was able to click on the okay button
successfully but previously it was not
even able to uh scan this particular
control okay so uh in scenarios where
you're not able to scan uh particular
controls using the application option
you can go ahead and choose a different
option in the xcan window there are
different options like UIA you can also
follow back up on Vision AI if you have
got an account for that okay so these
are the two different options which you
can try before falling back to different
other options right now uh this uh will
work for the Chrome browser so if you
are working on other browsers the
message may be different or the popup
title may be different so you need to
adjust your uh name name of that
particular title as per the browser
window because every browser will have a
different title for the JavaScript
popup that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video